(
"ai_sub_version": "2.9.1",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 7,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 15,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch"
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 5,
"max": 5,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
HAPPY MUSIC
どうかしてる
Something is wrong with me,
また同じシャツを
searching for that same shirt again.
いないはずの
Even though you shouldn't be there,
人混みに探してた
I was searching for you in the crowd.
だれといても
No matter who I'm with,
何を話しても
no matter what we talk about,
映るすべて
everything that catches my eye,
やだ また重ねている
gosh, I keep overlapping it with you.
名前しか知らない
I only know your name,
なのにね こんなに
and yet, why is it that
気になるの…これって
I'm so curious about you... could this be,
もしかして
by any chance...?
ほら たった今
Look, right at this moment,
あたしのなかで
inside of me,
運命の針を胸に落として
Dropping the needle of fate into my chest,
奏でる
I play it.
大事な日も まじめな時も
On important days and during serious times,
手加減なしの パワープレイ
it's an all-out power play!
誰よりも先
Ahead of anyone else,
あなたを見つけたくて
I want to find you.
ダーリン 今度も
Darling, next time too,
あのシャツきてきて
wear that shirt, okay?
こんぬいー！
Kon-nui!
ホロライブ3期生の不知火フレアでーす！
I'm Shiranui Flare from Hololive's 3rd generation!
この度は、不知火フレア2026、BEMANI楽曲3Dライブ、始まりました！
The Shiranui Flare 2026 BEMANI Song 3D Live has begun!
1曲目、えー、Happy Music、えー、ゲーム尺で今回お届けさせていただきましたが、どうでしたか？
For our first song, we brought you "Happy Music" in its game-sized version. How did you like it?
今回この衣装は、あのー、ポエットちゃんに寄せてみてね、あの、ちょっと天使っぽい感じに、させていただきました。
For this outfit, I styled it after Poet-chan to give it a bit of an angelic feel.
Happy Music、大好きな楽曲なので、今回歌わせていただきました。
Since "Happy Music" is a song I love so much, I'm so happy I got to sing it.
今回はですね、えー、タイトルにもあるように、BEMANI楽曲ライブとなっております。
Today, as the title suggests, this is a BEMANI song live concert!
全部BEMANI楽曲で、構成させていただきました。ありがとうございます。
The entire setlist consists of BEMANI songs. Thank you so much!
コナミさんにね、あの、こんな熱い気持ちを、あの一方的にちょっとお伝えさせていただいたら、
When I passionately reached out to Konami to share my vision,
あの、全面的にですね、あのご協力してくださって、なんとですね、こう、見てください。
they were incredibly supportive and gave me their full cooperation! And look...
てれん！今回ステージすごいんですよ！
Ta-da! The stage this time is amazing!
これですね、あの、コナミさんから、あの、素材を、あの、お借りさせていただきました。
We actually borrowed all these assets directly from Konami.
全部、あの、ご用意していただいたりとかしまして。
They prepared everything for us!
ま、めちゃめちゃ可愛い。あの、フレアがポップン派なので、あの、すごい、だいたいポップンなんですけど、
It's just so cute! Since I'm a big Pop'n Music fan, most of it is themed around Pop'n,
DDRとか、あの、下のキーボードは、ノスタルジアなのか、
but there's also DDR, and this keyboard at the bottom... is it Nostalgia,
うーん、それともキーボードマニアなのか、どっちなんだい？みたいなところですけども。
or Keyboardmania? Which one is it? It's kind of like that...
まぁ、こんな感じでね、結構色んな、ここ、ここ、ごめんなさい、SOUND VOLTEXみたいな感じで、
But yeah, with elements like this—sorry, over here, it's like SOUND VOLTEX—
すごい、あの、BEMANI要素をつめつめにしたステージになりました。本当にありがとうございます。
it's become a stage packed with tons of BEMANI references. Thank you so much!
ご協力いただきまして、ありがとうございました。
Thank you so much for your cooperation.
ってな、あの、これは完全にフレアの、あの、やりたい放題みたいなライブになっておりますので。
Honestly, this concert is basically a self-indulgent live where I do whatever I want...
でもですね、なんかすごい、この、これが結果的にとっても嬉しいお知らせに、つながるかもしれない、つながらないかもしれない、
But you know, this might actually lead to some very exciting news down the road... or maybe it won't!
まぁ、それはちょっと、あの、今後の、お楽しみに、ということで。
Well, look forward to finding out in the future!
ハッシュタグは、えー、不知火フレア生誕祭2026でございます。
The stream hashtag is #ShiranuiFlareBirthdayFestival2026.
こちらでですね、あの、スクショとかポストとか、あの、色々、してもらえると、嬉しいです。
I'd love it if you could use that to share screenshots, posts, and everything else!
えー、この後、どんな曲が出てくるのかは、あの、完全にフレアが、
As for what songs are coming up next,
あの、好みとか、もう独断と偏見で選んでるので、あの、皆さんあの、楽しみにしながら、
I chose them purely based on my own personal bias and preferences. So, I hope you all...
えー、待っててもらえたら、嬉しいです。
look forward to it and stay tuned!
あの、知らない方もね、お、こんな曲があるんだ、と知ってもらえたら、嬉しいなと思います。
Even if you don't know the songs, I'd be happy if this helps you discover some great music.
明日はポップンしに行こうとかね、あの、SOUND VOLTEXしに行こうとかって
I'd be thrilled if this makes you want to go play Pop'n Music
気持ちになってくれたら嬉しいなって思うので、楽しみにしててください。
or SOUND VOLTEX tomorrow, so please look forward to the rest!
最後まで見てくれないと、ちょっと泣いちゃうかも。シクシク、えーんえーん、チラ。
If you don't watch until the very end, I might cry... *sniff sniff, sob sob, peek*
えーんえーん、泣いちゃうかも！
*wahhh*, I might really cry!
ナカナイデ
Don't cry
本当の孤独も知らない
You don't even know true loneliness
まだ淡い花びらに
In these still pale petals,
涙の粒 抱えたまま
holding droplets of tears...
ah さわらないで
Ah, don't touch me
暖かなその手は
Those warm hands of yours
あたしのすべて狂わす
drive everything about me crazy
ne 許さないで
Hey, don't forgive me
傷口を押さえて
Holding over my wounds,
微笑んでる あなたがいる
there you are, smiling
もう 帰れないね
I can't go back anymore, can I?
落ちてく時の甘い香り
The sweet scent of falling time
繰り返すたびにひどくなる
gets worse each time it repeats
ダキシメテ
Hold me close
いまだけ好きだってフリして
Just for now, pretend you love me
たったひとつだけなら
If I can have just one thing,
ぜんぶ ぜんぶ いらない
then I don't need anything, anything else
ナカナイデ
Don't cry
本当の孤独も知らない
You don't even know true loneliness
まだ淡い花びらに
In these still pale petals,
涙の粒 抱えたまま
holding droplets of tears...
ah 急がないで
Ah, don't rush
真実なんか ほら
Because you see, the truth
どこにも落ちてないでしょ
isn't lying anywhere, is it?
ne 見つめないで
Hey, don't stare at me
やさしいまなざしを
With that gentle gaze...
憎んでいる? 求めている?
Do I hate it? Or do I long for it?
もう わからなくて
I don't even know anymore
キスするときのあたしの顔
My face when we kiss...
あたしの顔
...my face...
もっと綺麗に見せたいだけ
...I just want to show it to you more beautifully.
抱きしめて いつでも かわいいフリして
Hold me tight, always pretending to be cute.
真っ赤に色づく実を ずっとずっと待ってる
I'm always, always waiting for the fruit to ripen to bright red.
泣かないで 本当の 自分も知らずに
Don't cry, without even knowing who you truly are.
まだ淡い花びらに 夢の重さ抱えたまま
Still carrying the weight of dreams on these pale petals.
堕ちてゆく時の 甘い香り
The sweet fragrance of the moment we fall.
繰り返すたびに 酷くなる
Every time it repeats, it only gets worse.
抱きしめて 今だけ 好きだってフリして
Hold me tight, just for now, pretend that you love me.
たったひとつだけなら 全部全部いらない
If I can have only one thing, then I don't need anything else at all.
Bloomin' like a Rose 本当の 孤独も知らない
Bloomin' like a Rose, without even knowing true loneliness,
まだ淡い花びらに 涙の粒抱えたまま
still carrying tear droplets on these pale petals.
あと３センチ
Just 3 more centimeters...
キミのくちびるまで
...until I reach your lips.
妄想つむぐ
Spinning my delusions.
イカした夢はなぜか
For some reason, my cool dream...
これからってトコで いつもさめる
...always wakes up right when things are getting good.
わずかに10センチ
Just a mere 10 centimeters...
のばす腕むなしく
...as I stretch out my arm in vain.
SHUT! 閉まる扉
Shut! The closing doors.
ホームにひとり キミと
Alone on the platform, with you...
ガラスごしに
...through the glass...
目と目があう
...our eyes meet.
あぁ ここはひとつ 笑うしかない
Ah, at this point, I can only laugh.
白線のうしろ 立ち上がんだ
I stand up behind the white line.
不覚にも涙がこぼれても
Even if tears unexpectedly spill over...
チェイス! ここはひとつ 笑うしかない
Chase! At this point, I can only laugh.
いつかキミまで追いつくかな
I wonder if I'll ever catch up to you?
帰って捨てちゃうほど
Enough that I might go home and throw it away,
かわりはいるぞなんて
saying things like "there's plenty of replacements"...
ううん どうなの?
No, what is that really about?
おじいちゃん おばあちゃん
Grandpa, Grandma,
すぐに投げちゃいけないんだよね
we shouldn't just throw things away easily, right?
今も昔もこれからもずっと
Now, in the past, and forever,
かわりに僕はどこにもいない
there is no replacement for me anywhere.
もう ここはひとつ 笑うしかない
By now, at this point, I can only laugh.
わかりあえる その日が来るまで
Until the day we can fully understand each other.
いつか　キミまで　追いつくかな
I wonder if I'll catch up to you someday
ふたりの　距離は　縮まるかな
I wonder if the distance between us will shrink
ノドの　乾きも　忘れたまま
With my dry throat completely forgotten
終わらないよ Chase!
It won't end, Chase!
キミの代わりは　ひとりもいない
There is not a single replacement for you
キミの代わりじゃ　ボクはいらない
If it's a replacement for you, I don't want it
不覚にも　涙がこぼれても
Even if tears unintentionally fall
もう　ここはひとつ　笑うしかない
Now all I can do is laugh
今も昔も　これからずっと
Now, in the past, and forevermore
かわりの僕は　どこにもいない
There is no replacement for me anywhere
あぁ　そうだったのかって　きっと　きっと
Ah, realizing "so that's how it was," surely, surely
わかりあえる　その日が来るから
Because the day we can understand each other will come
Chase! 今日もひとつ　笑うしかない
Chase! Today too, all I can do is laugh
闇に放り込んだ
Cast into the darkness
想い届いていますか？
Are my thoughts reaching you?
浅い夢の覚め際に毎日
Every day, upon awakening from a shallow dream
伝う涙の理由はどこから
Where does the reason for these trickling tears come from?
きっと戻ってくると　頬を撫でる手は冷たくて
"I will surely return," you said, with a hand caressing my cheek so cold
ぎゅっと広い背中を　抱きしめた
I tightly embraced your broad back
謳え　謳え　通い路恋歌
Sing, sing, the love song of our path
たとえ声はしなくとも
Even if my voice cannot be heard
届け　届け　通い路恋歌
Reach, reach, the love song of our path
愛する人の為　ずっと笑顔で居るから
Because I will always wear a smile for the one I love
淡い日々の思い出に毎日
Every day in the memories of those fleeting days
すがる二人の姿は儚げ
The figures of the two of us clinging together seem so transient
ぐっと押さえ続けた　瞳の奥のやさしさが
The gentleness deep within my eyes that I firmly held back
ふっと帰り咲く刹那に　溢れる心
At the moment it suddenly blooms again, my heart overflows
止まれ　止まれ　防人恋歌
Stop, stop, the soldier's love song
たとえ声はしなくとも
Even if my voice cannot be heard
届け　届け　通い路恋歌
Reach, reach, the love song of our path
愛する人の為　ずっと笑顔で居るから
Because I will always wear a smile for the one I love
貴方の為　君の為　また出会う日までの約束
For you, for you, a promise until the day we meet again
どんな思いが馳せようと　笑顔で居よう
No matter what thoughts may race, let's keep smiling
遠く　遠く　わかれても
Even if we are separated far, far away
辛い時は　歌に乗せて
When times are tough, let's put it into a song
ずっと待っているよと　しがみつく手は震えてて
"I'll be waiting forever," you said, with your clinging hand trembling
もっと強く深く深く　抱きしめた
I embraced you even tighter, deeper and deeper
謳え　謳え　通い路恋歌
Sing, sing, the love song of our path
たとえ声が枯れても
Even if my voice withers away
笑え　笑え　通い路恋歌
Laugh, laugh, the love song of our path
あたたかい陽はまだか ずっと　ずっと　謳えるのは
Is the warm sun not here yet? The reason I can sing on and on...
君の声がするから
...is because I can hear your voice
はい！
Hi!
皆さん！
Everyone!
見てますか？
Are you watching?
はい、ということでですね、あきちゃんとはピンクローズを、リィカとは、えー、チェイス！チェイス！チェイス！
Yes, and so, with Aki-chan, [I sang] Pink Rose, and with Rika, uh, Chase! Chase! Chase!
です。そして、え、防人恋歌を、ソロで歌わせていただきましたー！
Yes. And, um, I got to sing "Sakimori Renka" solo!
はい。ま、ちょっとね、あの、どうしてこの曲を選んだかみたいなのはね、ま、ちょっとあの、その、なんかの、世代じゃないんですけど、
Yes. Well, as for why I chose this song... Well, it's not really like it's from my generation, but...
なんかこの、好きな曲とか、なんか合いそうな曲、あとは、ま、みんながね、あの、親しんだポップンと言えば、みたいな、
...it's a song I like, and a song that seems to suit me. Also, it's a song that everyone's familiar with when they think of pop'n...
曲だったり、ま、あの、ピンクローズはね、キーボードマニアの曲なんですけど。
...or, well, "Pink Rose" is actually from Keyboardmania, though.
ま、でも、みんな好きな曲をちょっと選曲したら、バラバラなのでね。とか、
But, well, when I chose songs that everyone likes, they were all over the place. Or...
ま、防人恋歌は、もう、思い、思い出がありすぎてヤバい。
...well, "Sakimori Renka" has way too many memories, it's crazy.
ヤバいんですけど、あの、好きな曲だったので、ちょっとチョイスさせていただきました。いや本当にでも難しかったです。
It's crazy, but since it's a song I love, I chose it. But seriously, it was really difficult.
でもですね、え、今日はですね、あの、衣装変わりましたけれども、
But anyway, today, although my outfit has changed,
今日はなんとですね、え、私の、あの、希望で、え、今回、ポップンミュージック、
today, surprisingly, at my request, this time, for pop'n music...
ハイ・チアーズを遊べると、聞いたんですけど。
...I heard that we can play "High Cheers!"?
え？どこで、どこにあるんでしょう？ちょっと、探してみましょうか。
Huh? Where? Where is it? Let's go look for it.
どこどこどこどこ、どこどこどこ。
Where, where, where, where, where is it?
はっ！これは！
Ah! This is...!
わあー！会いたかった！
Wow! I wanted to see this!
大好き！え、すごいよ、これ。この技術はすごい技術ですよ。
I love it! Wow, this is amazing. This technology is incredible!
皆さん、なかなか、あの、VTuberが実機で遊んでいるところを見る機会がね、なかなか無いと思うんですけど。
Everyone, I think there aren't many opportunities to see a VTuber playing on an actual arcade cabinet like this, but...
いや本当に、あの、コナミさん、そして運営さん、本当にありがとうございます。
...seriously, Konami-san, and the staff, thank you so much.
今回はね、こちらの可愛い筐体で遊ばせていただくんですけれども、
This time, I get to play on this cute cabinet,
あの、皆さん、このステージ気づきました？こちらはですね、なんとスピーカー、このスピーカーとかですね、あの、
but did everyone notice this stage? Here, surprisingly, the speakers, like these speakers...
ステージ側にもあるんですけれども、こちらね、合わせていただいたりとかして、
...and also on the stage side, they matched them up for us,
コナミさんがね、あの、ステージ素材をね、あの、ご用意してくださったんですよ。いや本当に、本当にありがとうございます！
and Konami-san prepared the stage assets for us! Seriously, thank you so much!
なんかコナミさんにオンブにダッコで、本当にすみません。
I'm really sorry for leaning so heavily on Konami-san like this.
私の今日やりたいことをたくさん、あの、お願いして、あの、ダメ元でお願いしたらね、あの、たくさん応えてくださって本当にありがとうございます。
I asked for so many things I wanted to do today, just asking on the off chance, and you answered so many of them. Thank you so much.
頭が上がりませんが、あの、せっかくなんでね、早速ちょっと遊ばせていただこうかなと思います。
I can't thank you enough, but since I have the chance, I'd like to start playing right away.
では、ちょっと、いいですか？
So, can I go ahead?
とりあえずハッピーバースデーのとこ叩かせていただいて。
First of all, let me hit the Happy Birthday buttons.
ポンポンポンポンポン、これ、この画面にね、あの、クラッカーが映ったりとかするんですけれど。
*pop pop pop pop* This... party poppers appear on this screen, you see.
今回は、えー、自分の、あの、マイカードで遊ばせて、
This time, um, I get to play using my own card...
いただけるということで、
...which is awesome!
あ、ちょっと暗証番号は見せられないので、ちょっと待ってくださいね。
Oh, I can't show you my PIN code, so please wait a moment.
はい。こうして、ちょちょいのちょいと、入れさせていただきますよ。
Okay, let me just enter it real quick like this.
うわあ！ポップンミュージックだ！
Whoa! It's Pop'n Music!
いつも遊ばせていただいております。お世話になっております。ありがとうございます。
I play it all the time. Thank you for your continued support!
ということでですね、今日は、推しを使わせていただきます。
And so, today, I'll be using my favorite character (Oshi).
ちょっとね、今回は、あの、ボーカル・ライブということで、
This time, since it's a vocal live,
あの、ボーカル縛りちょっと3曲をね、選ばせていただこうと思ったんですけど。
I thought of choosing three songs restricted to vocals.
今日のラインナップ、え、3曲は、
Today's lineup of three songs is...
ポップンミュージックで一番好きな曲、おと、おとで、まず遊ばせていただこうかと思います。
I'd like to start by playing my absolute favorite song in Pop'n Music first.
もうね、大好きなんですよね。
I just love it so much!
でもあの、ちょっとハイパーで許していただきたいと思います。
But, please forgive me for playing it on Hyper difficulty.
今日選ぶ3曲の中で、個人的には一番難しい。
Out of the three songs I'm choosing today, personally, this is the hardest.
難しいです。
It's really hard.
難しかったんですけど、もう一番大好きな曲なので、ちょっと選ばせていただきました。
It was hard, but since it's my absolute favorite, I decided to choose it.
ボーカルでこの曲選んでいいのかって話なんですけど。
I wonder if it's okay to choose this song for vocal...
いや、この静かに始まる感じとね。
I love this quiet beginning.
あの、最後に来る縦連とかが難しいんですよね。
The rapid vertical taps at the end are really hard.
これ配信バフでフルコンとかできないかな？無理か。
I wonder if I can get a Full Combo with stream buff? No way, right?
ちょっと音ゲーマー、あ、コンボ繋がってるときは喋れないって、あ、切れちゃいましたね。
I'm becoming a real rhythm gamer—ah, I thought I couldn't talk while keeping a combo, oh, it broke.
ああ、右手に、右手に推し、左手に推し、幸せですね。
Ah, my favorite on my right hand, my favorite on my left hand, I'm so happy!
ああ！
Ah!
ああ、縦連が苦手なんです。許してください。
Ah, I'm bad at rapid vertical taps. Please forgive me!
らいなわっしょい
Right now, WASSHOI!
この曲も
This song, too...
歌いたかったですね
...is one I wanted to sing.
また、もしまたなんか機会があったら、歌わせてください
If there is another opportunity, please let me sing it.
どうしてもちょっと後半がグズグズになってしまう
Somehow the latter half always gets sloppy.
あー、神曲！
Ah, what a god-tier song!
ここがきつい！
This part is tough!
あ、なんか取れたかな？大丈夫かな？
Ah, did I get some sort of record? Is it okay?
あ、一番、フレアが一番好きな曲です
Ah, it's Flare's absolute favorite song.
これで音読みます
With this, I'll load the chart.
あー大好き。あの、推しです。
Ah, I love it. He's my fave.
推しのMZDさんです、これどちらも。
My favorite MZD-san, both of them.
今日はですね、あの、選ぶ3曲のうちの2曲がちょっとMZDの曲なんですけど
Today, two of the three songs I chose are MZD's,
どうしてもみんなとやりたかった曲もあって、ちょっとそれ最後にしたいなと思ったんで、ちょっとMZDで挟んじゃうんですけど
but there's a song I absolutely wanted to play with everyone, so I wanted to put it at the end, meaning MZD's songs sandwich it.
今回、ちょっとライブは歌わないのですが
I won't be singing live this time...
やはりね、ポップンと言えばの中で
...but when people think of pop'n...
結構「凛として咲く花の如く」じゃないかっていう方もたくさんいらっしゃったので
...many said "Rin to Shite Saku Hana no Gotoku,"
ちょっと「凛として咲く花の如く」を叩かせていただこうかと思います。よろしくお願いします。
so I'd like to play "Rin to Shite Saku Hana no Gotoku." Please look forward to it.
ちょっと速度の調整は大丈夫そうです。これでいきます。
The speed adjustment seems fine. Let's go with this.
凛として咲く花の如く
Rin to Shite Saku Hana no Gotoku
みんなの1番いい曲の1つですね。
It's one of everyone's best songs.
1番いい曲なんて何番あったっていいですからね。
There can be as many "best songs" as you want.
そりゃ今日何回「一番いい曲の1つ」って言ってるでしょう
I've probably said "one of the best songs" so many times today.
口癖みたいに言ってると思います
I think I'm saying it like a habit.
これエルフレにもたくさん知ってもらいたいんですよね。
I really want the Elfriends to know about this.
コナミさんのオリジナル曲にはたくさんいい曲があるということを...
There are so many great Konami original songs...
つい歌いがち
I tend to sing along without thinking.
ここがね... このあと！
This part... and then after this!
こういうところ好きですよねー
I love parts like this!
いや、いい曲であり、譜面もいい
It's a great song, and the chart is also great.
ちょっとお馬さんパカパカみたいな感じで
It feels a bit like a horse trotting.
ここ楽しいですよね
This part is so fun!
ということで、ギリギリ、スコアが9万点いかないみたいな
And so, just barely, my score didn't reach 90,000...
これちょっと悔しいですね
...which is a bit frustrating.
はい、凛として、あ、ニューレコードだそうです。
Yes, Rin to Shite... Oh, it says new record.
これ自分のマイカードなので、やっぱ配信バフなんでしょうか。ありがとうございました。
Since this is my personal card, is it the stream buff? Thank you very much!
最後はですね、みんなでどうしても叫びたかったあの曲といったら、2択だと思うんですけど
For the last one, when it comes to that song we absolutely wanted to scream together, I think there are two choices...
ちょっとどうしてもみんなと叫びたい、ハンズアップに決まってるじゃないですか！
I really want to scream with everyone, of course it's hands up!
これ知らない方はね、あの、カウントのあとカウントあります。
If you don't know it, after the countdown, there is a countdown.
4, 3, 2, 1でサニーステージなんで、皆さんで叫びましょう
It goes 4, 3, 2, 1, then Sunny Stage! Let's scream it together!
叫べるかな？ちょっと45だけど、これ45じゃないんじゃないかっていう
Can we scream it? It's level 45, but doesn't it feel like it's not a 45?
なんか最後がすごい難しいですよね。速度落としたらごめんなさい。
The end is really difficult. I'm sorry if I fail.
これ、みんなで叫ぶのが夢だったんですよね。
It was my dream to shout this together with everyone.
ホールドラッシュとね、どっちやろうかなって迷いましたらば、ちょっと、セカンドヘブンにしました。
I was wondering whether to play 'Hold Rush' or this, but I ended up choosing 'Second Heaven'.
なんか、ボーカル縛りと言いながら、2曲英語っていう...
I said it was a vocal-only selection, but two of the songs are in English...
あ、カウントダウン、一緒にしよう！
Ah, let's do the countdown together!
7, 6, 5, 4, 3, 2, 1...
サンバディスクリーム！！！
Somebody scream!!!
みんなちゃんとやりました？
Did everyone do it properly?
もう1回やりますからね。
We'll do it one more time, okay?
正しい歌詞は、ぜひ調べてください。
Please look up the correct lyrics yourself!
あ、生きがいなんだ。Somebody screamって言うことが生きがいなんだ。
Ah, it's my purpose in life. Saying 'Somebody scream' is my purpose in life!
みんなはこの配信を見た後、明日ポップンやりに行きましょうね。
After watching this stream, everyone should go play Pop'n tomorrow!
人の配信見てるとやりたくなりますからね。
Watching someone else play makes you want to play it too, right?
ちょっと恥ずかしいんですけど、手元見られてんの。
It's a bit embarrassing having people watch my hands.
サンバディスクリーム！！！
Somebody scream!!!
急に叫ぶよ。
I shout out of nowhere!
ちょっとここムズい。
It's a bit hard here.
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
あー、みんなで「Somebody scream」が言えて、幸せだー！
Ah, I'm so happy we could all say 'Somebody scream' together!
いや、本当にありがとうございました。
Really, thank you very much.
あ、待って、でも3曲終わっちゃった。終わっちゃったよー！
Oh, wait, but the three songs are already over. It's already over!
あー、楽しかったー！
Ah, that was so fun!
もうなんか、今日はね、あの3曲しか遊べないので、ここで終わってしまうんですけど、あの実機プレイはここで終わっちゃうんですけど...
Well, since I can only play three songs today, the actual gameplay ends here, but...
嫌だ！やだやだ、離れたくない、ポップンと！
No! I don't want to leave Pop'n!
うわーん、やだ！今日はもうポップンすると...ポップンと離れたくなーい！
Waaah, no! I don't want to leave Pop'n!
うわーん、ポップンしたいよー！
Waaah, I want to play Pop'n!
まあ、無いものはしょうがないか。ちょっと切り替えていきますか。
Well, can't do anything about what we don't have. Let's switch gears.
まだですね、あの、この後も、みんなの好きな一番良い曲たくさん歌いますので、ちょっと楽しみにして、この後も観てもらえたら嬉しいなって思います。
There is still more, I'll be singing a lot of your favorite, best songs after this, so please look forward to it and continue watching!
じゃあみんな、次に行くぞ！何の次の曲は...
Alright everyone, let's move on to the next! The next song is...
ドハドハドハドハドハドハドハドハ ドパッ
Doha-doha-doha-doha-doha-doha-doha-doha dopa!
Yeah ドパドパ
Yeah, dopa-dopa!
回転頭からない言語
A language absent from rotating minds,
ハイテンションと固いテンポ
high tension and a solid tempo.
１先導するジャイケンちから大見解戦法
1: Leading with giant power, the Grand Interpretation tactic!
回転頭からない言語
A language absent from rotating minds,
ハイテンションと固いテンポ
high tension and a solid tempo.
１先導するジャイケンちから大見解戦法
1: Leading with giant power, the Grand Interpretation tactic!
354+2すらはじけぬコンパ好きに
To the party-lover who can't even solve 354+2,
あっさり鈍角にねじ込むさばけた音楽キ
easily twisting into an obtuse angle, a worldly-wise music spirit.
どっからどこまでかわらん？がわけた理由だ
The reason you don't know where it starts and ends,
どいつとこいつのしゃれくりが垂らした汗ふきな
wipe off the sweat dripped by their clever play.
テンダン変化つけだ ×電波に乗る
Changing the trend, riding the radio waves,
大変馬鹿げた発言な
an incredibly ridiculous statement.
グーを作りゃ 人格すら
When making a fist, even your personality...
変わる程に上がる心拍数は
changes as your heart rate rises.
たっぷりあこぎだが、におい棒を握ると力
It's quite cruel, but grasping the smelly rod brings power...
として生まれたときから 続けてきたこの遊び方
since the moment we were born, we have continued this way of playing!
回転頭からない言語
A language absent from rotating minds,
ハイテンションと固いテンポ
high tension and a solid tempo.
１先導するジャイケンちから大見解戦法
1: Leading with giant power, the Grand Interpretation tactic!
回転頭からない言語
A language absent from rotating minds,
ハイテンションと固いテンポ
high tension and a solid tempo.
１先導するジャイケンちから大見解戦法
1: Leading with giant power, the Grand Interpretation tactic!
3通りから4通り 本当理より凡道理
From 3 ways to 4 ways, common sense over true logic,
まかせたきりを梱包し がっつり温厚に
packing up whatever was left to us, staying completely gentle.
本当にこの鈍行に 跨がっていれば don't worry
If you really ride this local train, don't worry,
Don Pach Don Pach Don今日で とことん交尾する日本鳥に
Don Pach Don Pach Don, today, for the Japanese birds mating to the limit!
3通りから4通り 本当理より凡道理
From 3 ways to 4 ways, common sense over true logic,
まかせたきりを梱包し がっつり温厚に
packing up whatever was left to us, staying completely gentle.
本当にこの鈍行に 跨がっていれば don't worry
If you really ride this local train, don't worry,
Don Pach Don Pach Don今日で とことん交尾する日本馬に
Don Pach Don Pach Don, today, for the Japanese horses mating to the limit!
Don Pach Don Pach Don 今日で
Don Pach Don Pach Don, starting today...
とことん交尾する日本通り
Mating all the way on Japan Avenue!
とっちとっちとっちとっ調子
In a groove groove groove groove!
ぶち壊していくぜ日本通理だば
We're gonna wreck it, the Japanese way!
うわー！
Whoa!
[お米の美味しい炊き方、そしてお米を食べることによるその効果。]
[How to cook delicious rice, and the effects of eating rice.]
O!
K.O!
M.E!
RICE! おこめこめ
RICE! Rice, rice!
O!
K.O!
M.E!
RICE! おこめこめ RICE!
RICE! Rice, rice! RICE!
SUPER POWER RELAXATION
1) 1合150cc正確無比に量ること
1) Measure 1 cup of 150cc with absolute precision.
2) 次に洗いだが直接米にお水をあてず2本指で
2) Next is washing, but don't pour water directly onto the rice, use two fingers...
3) お水を量りJOIN!するのだがその米の1.2倍
3) Measure the water and JOIN! But the amount should be 1.2 times the rice.
その後は2時間ほどサディスティックにお水に浸して
After that, soak it in water sadistically for about 2 hours.
ジャーの電源
Power on the rice cooker!
陽炎のような
Like a heat haze...
スチーム
Steam!
底から
From the bottom...
かき混ぜて
Stir it up!
おこめ おこめこめ ビタミン ミネラル 食物繊維
Rice, rice, rice! Vitamins, minerals, dietary fiber!
おこめ おこめこめ あ～食べてどすこい どすこい
Rice, rice, rice! Ah, eat it up, dosukoi dosukoi!
おこめ おこめこめ おすもうさんのPowerをGET
Rice, rice, rice! GET the power of a sumo wrestler!
おこめこめ おこめこめ あぁ抱いてロマンティックに
Rice, rice! Rice, rice! Ah, hold me romantically...
NIGHT FLIGHT
...on a NIGHT FLIGHT!
おこめ おこめこめ 4) 米屋のあの子をたぶらかそう！
Rice, rice, rice! 4) Let's seduce that girl from the rice shop!
炊き放題 食べ放題 SO I LOVE YOU GET DAZEー！
All-you-can-cook, all-you-can-eat, SO I LOVE YOU GET DAZE!
おこめ おこめこめ SUPER ENERGY MIRACLE POWER
Rice, rice, rice! SUPER ENERGY MIRACLE POWER!
おこめこめ おこめこめ
Rice, rice! Rice, rice!
あぁんおこめ あぁおこめ
Ah, rice! Ah, rice!
5) おこめおいしい
5) Rice is delicious!
[Homesick Pt.2&3]
真昼と真夜中の間に立つ歌は
The song standing between noon and midnight...
真っ白なゲームといって耳もとではしゃぐ
...plays a snow-white game and chatters in my ear.
パーフェクト 僕らは完璧…なんて軽い冗談だった
"Perfect, we are perfect..." was just a light joke.
いつも答えは 127の項目
The answer is always the 127 items.
アスファルト蹴りあげたらトランプで決めて
Once we kick up the asphalt, we'll decide with cards...
急ぎ足で駆け出すのさ 今すぐバスで
...and rush out right now on the bus.
そしてホームシック抱えながら人々は目指す
And while carrying our homesickness, people aim...
行き先はスマートに決めて 願いを叶えたいのなら
...to smartly decide the destination, if they want their wishes to come true.
真夏と真冬の間に生まれた歌は
The song born between midsummer and midwinter...
まったりなカーブ描いてどこまでも進む
...draws a relaxed curve and advances forever.
パーフェクト 全ては同じ…似たもの同士だった
"Perfect, everything is the same..." we were two of a kind.
いつも答えは同じ音なんだ
The answer is always the same sound.
ソフトロックで暴れたら
If we go wild with soft rock...
トークバックで yeah!
...yeah! With talkback!
差し出したルール 12月のスポーツ
The presented rule, a December sport.
バジルパスタの試食
A tasting of basil pasta.
明日の噂話をトランクに詰めて
Packing tomorrow's rumors into the trunk...
逆回しでやり直すのさ 悪い性格
...we start over in reverse, our bad personalities.
それでホームシック語りながら人々は祈る
And so, talking about homesickness, people pray...
行き先は満ちあふれてる 誰かが待ちわびるから
...for the destination is overflowing, because someone is waiting.
オレンジノイズ 浴びながら
Basking in the orange noise,
ショートカットで
taking a shortcut.
yeah!
新しいブーム
A new trend...
聞きあきたフレーズ
A phrase I'm tired of hearing...
バブルアワーの法則
The law of bubble hour.
さあ明日の噂話を トラックに載せて [!]さあ明日の噂話を トラックにのせて
Now, let's load tomorrow's rumors onto the truck,
風に乗せて薔薇撒くのさ [!]風に乗せてバラ撒くのさ
and scatter them on the wind.
誰の計画？
Whose plan is this?
そしてホームシック
And homesick,
笑いながら
while laughing,
人々は迷う
people wander.
行き先はそれぞれさ 皆
Everyone has their own destination,
旅の途中なんだから
since we're all in the middle of a journey.
風に乗って羽ばたくのは
To soar on the wind and flap wings
鳥の計画
is the birds' plan.
行き先はスピードを上げて
Speeding up towards our destination,
この先もまだ続くなら
if it still keeps going like this...
続くなら
If it keeps going...
If it keeps going......
続くなら
はい！ということで！
All right! So,
えー、聞いていただきました曲はですね、何て言えばいいですかね、ヒップロック？オコメタル？ソフトロック？ということで
the song you just heard was, how should I put it, hip-rock? Okometal? Soft rock?
えー、ポルカと1曲、バカタレサーカスで2曲ということで
So, one song with Polka, and two songs with Bakatare Circus.
なんかオコメタルとかでもね、バカタレサーカスでどうしてもやりたかったんですよね。
Even with Okometal, I really wanted to perform it with Bakatare Circus.
でもやっぱ歌のうまいメンバーなんでね、皆さん集まってソフトロックとかで暴れ散らかしたりしたいなって思ったり、
But since they're all great singers, I wanted everyone to get together and go wild with some soft rock...
ポルカとはね、やっぱりあの、Deatholosophyということで、デスロさんの曲を一緒に歌いたいなと思いましたんで、 [!]ポルカとはね、やっぱりあの、Deatholosophyということで、デスロさんの曲を一緒に歌いたいなと思いましたんで
And with Polka, since we sang 'Deatholosophy', I wanted to sing Des-ROW-san's song together,
このメンバーで、えー、選曲させていただきました！
so I chose the setlist with these members!
ゲストはね、まだまだ、あの、まだまだって言ったらあれですね、まだいるので、お楽しみにということで、
We still have... well, saying 'still' sounds weird, but we have more guests coming up, so please look forward to it!
ちょっと早いんですけど、先にですね、今回あの、ちょっとグッズの紹介をさせていただいてもよろしいでしょうか？ [!]ちょっと早いんですけど、先にですね、今回あの、ちょっとグッズの紹介をさせていただいてもよろしいでしょうか？
It's a bit early, but first, would it be okay if I introduce the merchandise for this event?
また後でですね、あのグッズの紹介もまた改めてさせていただきます。 [!]また後でですね、あのグッズの紹介もまた改めてさせていただきます。
I'll introduce the merch again later too.
えー、ではですね、行きます。えー、不知火フレア 誕生日記念2026！ [!]えー、ではですね、行きます。えー、不知火フレア 誕生日記念2026！
All right, here we go! Shiranui Flare Birthday Celebration 2026!
早速、えー、ちょっと一つずつ見ていきましょう！ [!]早速、えー、ちょっと一つずつ見ていきましょう！
Let's take a look at them one by one!
まずは一つ目、マフラータオル！ [!]まずは一つ目、マフラータオル！
First up, the muffler towel!
イラストはファルまろさんに描いていただきました。とっても可愛い！ [!]イラストはファルまろさんに描いていただきました。とっても可愛い！
The illustration was drawn by Farumaro-san. It's so cute!
持ち運びやすいサイズ感なので、ぜひたくさん使ってください！ [!]持ち運びやすいサイズ感なので、ぜひたくさん使ってください！
It's a very portable size, so please use it a lot!
二つ目は、こちら。タンブラー！ [!]二つ目は、こちら。タンブラー！
Second is this one. The tumbler!
イラストは、けーじょーさんに描いていただきました。 [!]イラストは、けーじょーさんに描いていただきました。
The illustration was drawn by Keijou-san.
今回なんと、コナミさんに特別許可をいただいて、推しのデザインに寄せさせていただきました！ [!]今回なんと、コナミさんに特別許可をいただいて、推しのデザインに寄せさせていただきました！
This time, we actually got special permission from Konami to base the design on my favorite!
ありがとうございます！ [!]ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
ムラクモ MZD のオマージュイラストなんですけど、 [!]ムラクモ MZD のオマージュイラストなんですけど、
It's an homage illustration of Murakumo MZD,
のんびり寝転ぶフレアの横には、相棒のノワちゃことエルフレも一緒のとっても可愛いイラストとなってます。可愛いすぎ！ [!]のんびり寝転ぶフレアの横には、相棒のノワちゃことエルフレも一緒のとっても可愛いイラストとなってます。可愛いすぎ！
and next to Flare lounging around are her buddies, Nowacha-ko and Elfre! It's such a cute illustration. Way too cute!
大容量で、1リットルくらい入って、持ち手も付いてて飲みやすいので、ぜひみんなにも使ってほしいです！ [!]大容量で、1リットルくらい入って、持ち手も付いてて飲みやすいので、ぜひみんなにも使ってほしいです！
It has a large capacity of about 1 liter, and it's easy to drink from with a handle, so I hope everyone uses it!
三つ目は、こちら。ぬいぐるみ付きスマホショルダー！ [!]三つ目は、こちら。ぬいぐるみ付きスマホショルダー！
Third is this one. The smartphone shoulder bag with plushie!
お出かけ衣装のぬいぐるみが付いたスマホショルダーです。 [!]お出かけ衣装のぬいぐるみが付いたスマホショルダーです。
It's a smartphone shoulder bag with a plushie of me in my outing outfit.
ケースではないので、様々な機種のスマホが入るんですけど、 [!]ケースではないので、様々な機種のスマホが入るんですけど、
Since it's not a case, it fits various smartphone models,
全機種対応ではないので、サイズが合わなかった人は、スマホ以外の小物を入れてください。ぜひ、いろんな場所に連れてってね！ [!]全機種対応ではないので、サイズが合わなかった人は、スマホ以外の小物を入れてください。ぜひ、いろんな場所に連れてってね！...
but it's not compatible with absolutely every model, so if it doesn't fit, please use it for other small items. Take it with you everywhere!
四つ目は、こちら。キャップ！ [!]四つ目は、こちら。キャップ！
Fourth is this one. The cap!
イラストの私とお揃いのキャップです。 [!]イラストの私とお揃いのキャップです。
It's matching with the cap I'm wearing in the illustration.
今回のコンセプトで、帽子はどうしても外せなかったので、前に出したものとは色とデザインを変えてみました。 [!]今回のコンセプトで、帽子はどうしても外せなかったので、前に出したものとは色とデザインを変えてみました。...
With this concept, I absolutely couldn't leave out a hat, so I changed the color and design from the previous one.
どっかな？可愛いかな？かっこいいかな？ [!]どっかな？可愛いかな？かっこいいかな？
How is it? Is it cute? Cool?
シンプルめなデザインなので、季節を問わず被れるキャップです。みんなもお揃いにしてくれたら嬉しいな！ [!]シンプルめなデザインなので、季節を問わず被れるキャップです。みんなもお揃いにしてくれたら嬉しいな！...
It's a simple design, so you can wear it in any season. I'd be happy if we match!
五つ目は、こちら。シチュエーションボイス！ [!]五つ目は、こちら。シチュエーションボイス！
Fifth is this. The situation voice!
フレアと一緒に公園デート！ [!]フレアと一緒に公園デート！
A park date with Flare!
今回のグッズのイラストに合ったような雰囲気のシチュエーションボイスがついてます。 [!]今回のグッズのイラストに合ったような雰囲気のシチュエーションボイスがついてます。...
It's a situation voice with an atmosphere that fits the merch illustration.
みんな、よかったら聞いてね！ [!]みんな、よかったら聞いてね！
I hope you all check it out!
最後に、フルセット！ [!]最後に、フルセット！
Lastly, the full set!
数量限定は、直筆メッセージ入りチェキ風ブロマイドカード！ [!]数量限定は、直筆メッセージ入りチェキ風ブロマイドカード！
The limited edition includes a handwritten message cheki-style bromide card!
通常版は、箔押し複製メッセージ入りチェキ風ブロマイドカードが付いてきます。 [!]通常版は、箔押し複製メッセージ入りチェキ風ブロマイドカードが付いてきます。...
The regular edition comes with a hot-stamped replica message cheki-style bromide card.
ふう、駆け足だったけど、どれも凄く可愛くて使いやすいと思うので、ぜひみんな買ってもらえると嬉しいです！ [!]ふう、駆け足だったけど、どれも凄く可愛くて使いやすいと思うので、ぜひみんな買ってもらえると嬉しいです！...
Phew, that was quick, but I think all of them are super cute and practical, so I'd be really happy if you got them!
えー、じゃあ、次の曲に行こうかな？ [!]えー、じゃあ、次の曲に行こうかな？
Well then, shall we move on to the next song?
ゲストは、ちょっと、まだいるので、嬉しい告知とかも残っ…残ってる？ [!]ゲストは、ちょっと、まだいるので、嬉しい告知とかも残っ…残ってる？
There are still more guests to come, and some exciting announcements left... left?
映ってるかな？
Am I on screen?
みんなまだ帰らないでね！
Everyone, don't leave yet!
この後も楽しんでね！
Keep enjoying what comes next!
追いかけても
Even if I chase after you,
するり 指をぬける 水のように
Like water slipping through my fingers,
あなただけに
Only to you,
見つめられて 漂う 星のように
Like a star floating under your gaze,
夢でも つかまえて
Catch me, even in a dream.
流れる 雲に 想う
I think about the flowing clouds,
行き先ない この心
this heart with nowhere to go.
いつか見た 日の明日も
Even the tomorrow of the day I once saw
蒼い通り雨
is a blue passing shower.
色づいた 花びら 揺らす
Swaying the colored petals,
温もりも 激しささえも
both the warmth and the intensity...
切なさの
only the reverse side...
裏側だけを
of sadness...
残していくだけの
is left behind in this...
刹那
fleeting moment.
かなうのなら
If it can come true,
駆け出して行きたい 風の中
I want to run out into the wind.
あなただけを
Only you,
見つめたなら 羽ばたく 蝶のように
If I gaze at you, like a fluttering butterfly,
夢なら 見せないで
if it's a dream, please don't show me.
星のない 夜に 密か
Secretly on a starless night,
巡る季節を忘れて
forgetting the passing seasons.
いつか来る日の 朝を
The morning of a day that will come sometime
隠す 涙色
hides behind the color of tears.
絡む指 艶めく 吐息
Intertwined fingers, glossy sighs,
昇りつめ 堕ちゆく 心
a heart that rises to the peak and falls.
ひとときの 温もりさえも
Even a temporary warmth...
忘れられずに また ひとり
I cannot forget, and I am alone again.
追いかけたら
If I chase after you,
奪い消えてしまう 月の影
the moon's shadow will snatch you away.
わたしだけに
Only to me,
触れられたら 煌めく 星のように
If you could touch me, like a shining star,
嘘なら 抱きしめて
if it's a lie, hold me close.
届くのなら
If it reaches you,
明日さえ いらない 戻らない
I don't even need tomorrow, I won't go back.
離れてても
Even if we're apart,
心 焦がす 炎は あなただけ
The flame scorching my heart is only for you.
追いかけても
Even if I chase after you,
するり 指をぬける 水のように
Like water slipping through my fingers,
わたしだけが
Only I...
時を止めたように ただ 手を伸ばす
as if time had stopped, just reach out my hand.
かなうのなら
If it can come true,
駆け出して行きたい 風の中
I want to run out into the wind.
あなただけに
Only to you,
心 巡らす 遙か 朧月
My heart revolves around the distant hazy moon,
嘘でも 抱きしめて
hold me close, even if it's a lie,
夢なら 醒めないで
if it's a dream, please don't wake me.
世界が輝く その瞬間
The moment the world shines,
ちょっとでも 触れたくって
I just want to touch it, even a little.
ごらん 幻をのぞいて
Look, peering at the illusion,
空間が 重なって 溶け合う
the spaces overlap and melt together.
太陽と月のように
Like the sun and the moon,
時間を超えては つながる
connecting across time.
大胆不敵な 空想の輪郭を追いかけて
Chasing the bold and fearless contours of fantasy,
広がっては 飲み込んでいく
it spreads and consumes.
世界が輝く その瞬間
The moment the world shines,
ちょっとでも 触れたくって
I just want to touch it, even a little.
ごらん 幻をのぞいて
Look, peering at the illusion,
空間を 飛び越した
and leaped over space,
未来を 追い越す その瞬間
the moment I overtake the future.
いつでも こんなものなのさ
It's always like this.
幻をのぞいた 僕らの
Our illusion we peered at...
世界が 溶け合う
our worlds melt together.
始まりと終わりのように
Like a beginning and an end,
響きあう音の感情
Resonating emotions of sounds,
記憶を辿れば
If you trace the memories,
つながる
they connect.
変幻自在に
Assemble freely and changeably,
組まれた想像のパズルは
the puzzle of imagination
狂おしいほど美しいのだろう
must be beautiful to the point of madness.
世界を飛び立つその瞬間
That moment when you take off into the world,
どうしても見せたくて
I wanted to show you no matter what.
ごらんよ
Look!
見慣れない風景に
At the unfamiliar scenery,
そうさ今 駆け出した
that's right, now, I started running.
未来が不安だった昨日は
Yesterday, when the future was uncertain,
ちっぽけな
is just a tiny,
何気ない今日なのさ
casual today.
幻が歪んだボクらの
Our world, where the illusion is distorted,
世界が
our world...
重なる
...overlaps.
本当はずっと
The truth is, all along...
世界はボクを待ってた
...the world had been waiting for me.
本当はずっと
The truth is, all along...
ボクも君を待っていたんだ
...I had been waiting for you, too.
重なり合った
Our overlapping...
声が遠く響いて届く
...voices resonate and reach far away.
聞こえるでしょう
You can hear it, right?
目をあけて
Open your eyes,
物語が始まる時さ
it's time for the story to begin.
世界が輝くその瞬間
That moment when the world shines,
ちょっとでも触れたくて
I wanted to touch it even just a little.
ごらんよ
Look!
幻をのぞいて
Peek through the illusion
空間を飛び越した
and jump across space.
未来を追い越すその瞬間
That moment when you overtake the future,
いつでも こんなものなのさ
it's always just like this.
幻をのぞいたボクらの
Our world, where we peeked through the illusion,
世界が
our world...
溶け合う
...melts together.
はい！ということで聞いていただきました。
Yes! So, those were the songs you just heard.
オボロ、ハルモニア、2曲、どうでしたか？
'Oboro' and 'Harmonia'. How did you like the two songs?
オボロは俺の親友、アイリスと2人で
For 'Oboro', my close friend IRyS and I...
なんと大元のダンスを踊らせていただきました！
actually danced the original choreography!
超難しかった！
It was super difficult!
まぁどちらもね、大好きな曲なので
Well, both of them are my favorite songs,
ちょっと今回ね、歌えてすごく嬉しかったです。
so I'm really happy I got to sing them this time.
はい。ここまでもですね、盛りだくさんだったんですけど、
Yes. It's been packed with content so far, but...
ちょっとまだですね、ちょっと嬉しいことがありまして、
actually, there's still one more exciting thing!
なんとですね、今回あの、ちょっとビッグな
And that is, we have a very big guest...
ちょっと方をお呼びさせていただきまして、
...whom we have invited to join us today.
BEMANIシリーズで、あの、ちょっと作曲をしてくださっている方をね、ちょっとお呼びしたんですけど、
He has composed music for the BEMANI series.
誰かな？誰かな？と。ちょっと待ってくださいね。
I wonder who it is? Just a second.
誰かな？誰が...
Who could it be? Who...
えっ、だ、いいんですかね？これちょっと、いいですか？えー、
Oh, is this okay? Is it really okay? Uh...
あの、私が一番好きな曲と言っていました、
Well, the person who made the track...
えー、音を作っております、
...for my absolute favorite song...
wacさんです！
...is wac-san!
くるり
(Twirl)
どうも、よろしくお願いします。
Hello, nice to meet you.
あ、よろしくお願いします！今日はありがとうございます。
Ah, nice to meet you! Thank you so much for today.
ええ、ありがとうございます。
Yeah, thank you.
2Dだったんですね、これちょっと。 / あります。
Oh, so you're in 2D! / I can do this.
なんか下も伸びませんでした？
Didn't your bottom stretch just now?
下はね、伸びるんですよ。にょーっと。
The bottom part stretches, you see. Like this.
あ、結構長い！
Ah, it's pretty long!
ま、今日はね、これが精一杯なんですわ。はい。
Well, this is the limit of what I can do today. Yes.
今日はこれで許してほしいとのことなんですけど。あの、ちょっと自己紹介をしていただいてもよろしいでしょうか？
So we should forgive him for today. Um, could you please introduce yourself?
あ、おそれいります。東京都江東区...
Ah, certainly. From Koto Ward, Tokyo...
あ、言う、言っちゃっていいんですか？
Ah, are you sure you should say that?
コナミアミューズメントからやってまいりました、新人VTuberのwacです。
...from Konami Amusement, I am the rookie VTuber, wac.
よろしくお願いします！ / 困惑...
We look forward to working with you! / Bewildered...
「誰？」って感じなんですかね？それとも「何？」って感じなんですかね？
Is everyone thinking 'Who?' Or maybe they are thinking 'What?'
最近あの、よくね、あの、ライブリィとかでもやらせていただいておる、いるので、
Lately, I've been playing with you on Lively and stuff,
結構うちのリスナーとかも、知ってるとか、
so my listeners probably know who you are.
元々音ゲーマーさんとかも、結構知ってくださって、見てると思うんで、wacさんのことは多分知ってると思います。
Also, many rhythm gamers probably know you already, so they must know wac-san.
「あれ？これもwacさんなんだ」みたいなの結構あとから。
A lot of people probably realized later, like, 'Oh, wac-san made this too!'
そうです。奥から奥から、はい、色々出ますからね。
Yes. More and more of my songs will keep popping up.
はい、色々、そうなんですけど。
Yes, indeed.
一旦ちょっと、あの、遊ばせていただいた、あの、新筐体の話とか、
So, about the new arcade cabinet we just played on...
あ、ぜひ！
Ah, yes, please!
あの、12月18日とかでしたっけ？稼働。
It was launched on December 18th, right?
12月18日より順次稼働させていただいております、はい。
Yes, we've been rolling it out sequentially since December 18th.
はい。ぴかぴかポップくんモデル！
Yes! The shiny Pop-kun model!
先ほど遊ばせていただいたんですけど、
I got to play on it earlier,
いや、可愛いですね、見た目すごい！
and it looks so cute!
ですよね、めちゃくちゃ可愛いですよね。
Right? It's super cute, isn't it?
あの、あと、
Also...
個人的に、液晶がめちゃめちゃ明るくて、
Personally, I found the screen to be extremely bright,
すごい見やすいです。
which makes it really easy to see.
でっかいですもんね。
It's really big, too.
そうなんですよ。
That's true.
大きければ大きいほどいいですからね、はい。
The bigger, the better, after all.
そうですね、大きければ大きいほどいいです、はい、ありがとうございます。
Yes, the bigger the better indeed. Thank you.
あとあの、キャラクターがね、昔のキャラクターとかもすごい綺麗に映ったり、
Also, even the older characters are displayed so clearly on it,
する。 / はい。
which is great. / Yes.
そうですね、みなさんも本当に、今回ピカピカポップ君モデルが完成するまでには、ポップンスタッフのみんなもそうですけども
That's right, everyone. Honestly, before the Pikapika Pop-kun model was completed, well, the Pop'n staff too, of course...
DES-ROW先生や、wacさんや、DJ YOSHITAKAさんや、
...Des-ROW-sensei, wac, DJ YOSHITAKA-san,
PONさんや、猫叉Masterさんや、Takaさんや、あさきさんや、
PON-san, Nekomata Master-san, Taka-san, Asaki-san,
劇団レコードさん、KEIJI君、タリチュウ君...
Gekidan Record-san, KEIJI-kun, Tarichu-kun...
もういっぱいです。
There are just so many.
いいですか？そこまで(笑)
Is it okay to stop there? (laughs)
筐体作っていただいた方々も、筐体運んでくださった方々もいらっしゃいますし。
There are people who built the cabinet, and those who delivered it.
感謝の気持ちで、私生きております。
I live my life full of gratitude.
はい。この場に立てたのも、皆さんのおかげでございます。
Yes. Being able to stand here is all thanks to everyone.
はい、ありがとうござい... いや、それは本当にこちらがありがとうございます、なんですけれども。
Yes, thank—no, honestly, we should be the ones thanking you, but...
いえいえ、こうやってたどり着けたのも、いろんな方々のご尽力あってのことでございますので。
No, no, reaching this point was only possible thanks to the support of many people.
はい、ということなんですけれども。ポップンミュージックの、なんか初出し情報とかあります？
Right, indeed. Do you have any exclusive, first-reveal info about Pop'n Music?
それはちょっと...
That's a bit...
あ、言えない？
Oh, you can't say?
いや、言います。
No, I'll say it.
どっち？(笑)
Which is it? (laughs)
初出し情報って、何がいいですか？
What kind of exclusive info would you like?
私一個個人としては、やっぱりMZDの話とか聞きたいんですけども。
Personally, I'd really love to hear about MZD.
MZD？神ですね。
MZD? He's a god, after all.
はい、一番... / 神だから、あの、神ですね。
Yes, my favorite... / Since he's a god, well, he is a god.
ですし、結構やっぱりwacさんって、MZDの半分くらいだと思ってて。
And I feel like wac-san is about half of MZD...
半分？
Half?
残り半分はPONさんなんです。
...and the other half is PON-san.
えっとね、厳密にいうと、Mぐらいですね。
Well, strictly speaking, I'm only about "M".
ZがPONさんで、Dがその他みんなみたいな。
Z is PON-san, and D is everyone else.
あー、なるほど(笑) / くらいの配分ですね。
Ah, I see! (laughs) / That's roughly the distribution.
確かに確かに。なので、もし話せる範囲でMZDの話が聞けたら嬉しいなーって。
Indeed. So, if there's anything you can share about MZD within limits, I'd be happy.
なるほど。MZDの何を知りたいんだい？
I see. What do you want to know about MZD?
キャラ設定とか...
His character settings and such...
あ、確かアマゾン川流域青調ですね。
Ah, he's Amazon river basin blue-themed, right?
青基調。はい。
Blue-themed, yes.
何でかは知らんです。
I don't know why.
何で知らんのかい(笑)
Why don't you know?! (laughs)
でもなんか、昔アマゾンみたいな槍持ってましたよね。
But a long time ago, he held a spear that looked like an Amazon one.
影がですね。
His shadow did.
ありませんでした。なんですけど、今回あの
There were none. But this time...
なんと、今wacさんが言ってくださった通り、ちょっと、不知火フレア・BEMANIコラボ決定しました！
to my surprise, just like wac-san said earlier, the Shiranui Flare x BEMANI collaboration has been decided!
決定しました！ありがとうございます。
It's official! Thank you so much!
やったー！
Hooray!
やりましたね！やったね、ありがとうございます。めちゃめちゃ嬉しいです。ありがとうございます。
We did it! / We really did! Thank you so much. I'm so incredibly happy. Thank you!
おめでとうございます。ありがとうございます。
Congratulations! / Thank you.
なんか、えーと、どこを触れていいのかなと...
So, uh, I wonder where I should start...
どのゲームとしましょうか？っていうお話ですよね。
Which game should we collaborate with? That's what we should talk about.
え、ポップンポップンポップンポップン...
Oh, pop'n, pop'n, pop'n, pop'n...
ポップンしたいですね。
I want to do Pop'n Music.
まあ、そうですね。
Well, yes.
まあポップンさすがにここでしなかったらわけがわからないんですけども、ここまでして、はい。
I mean, if we didn't do pop'n after all this, it wouldn't make any sense. Yes.
そうですよね。
Right?
もちろんポップンもなんですけど、さらに今回、
Of course Pop'n, but in addition to that, this time...
SOUND VOLTEXと、DanceDanceRevolutionと、3機種でのコラボをさせていただきたいと思っております！
we're collaborating across three titles, including SOUND VOLTEX and DanceDanceRevolution as well!
すごい！これは、あの、私の曲が収録される...
Amazing! Does this mean my songs will be included...
それはもちろん。もちろん曲ですよ。新曲行きましょうよ。
Of course! Yes, songs. Let's go with a new song!
新曲？ / 新曲。
A new song? / A new song.
実はね、ちょっとね、この人がいいんじゃないかな、と思っているんですよね。曲作ってもらうなら。
Actually, I have someone in mind who would be great to write the song.
誰なんだろう？
Who could it be?
はい、先ほど、MとかZとかDとか、言ってたんで、
Yes, earlier we were mentioning M, Z, and D...
今回はその、Zにお願いしようかな、と思ってます。
so this time, I think we should ask Z.
Zって誰だっけ？
Who was Z again?
えーと、Z、Z誰だったっけ？
Let's see... Z, who was Z?
「ポ」ですね、ポ。ポ、ポです。
It's "Po", yes. Po. It's Po.
ポ、ポ、ポ、ポンです。P-O-N、ポンというね、あの、なかなかいい曲を書く子がいるんですよ、ポップンミュージック。
Po, po, po... Pon! P-O-N. PON is quite a talented person who writes really good songs for Pop'n Music.
ポ、ポンさん！
P-PON-san!
先ほど、そうですね、あの、フレアさんはM&Dの曲が好きっておっしゃってましたけど、まあ、1/3ぐらい作って、最近結構M&Dの曲いっぱい作ってますし、
Earlier, yes, Flare-san mentioned liking M&D's songs, but they write about 1/3 of them, and have written many M&D songs lately...
まあ、それ本人も歌うし、あの、女性ボーカリストの曲もいっぱい書いてるような、はい、P-O-N、ポンさんが...
And he sings them himself, and also writes many songs for female vocalists. Yes, P-O-N, PON-san...
私、あの、wacさんとポンさんが、あの、一番好きなんですよね。
Actually, wac-san and PON-san are my absolute favorites.
マジすか。ありがとうございます。
Really? Thank you very much.
もうなんか涙が出てきちゃう。
I feel like crying.
恐縮です。恥ずかしくて隠れちゃいます。あ、隠れて、出てきてください。
I'm honored. I'm going to hide out of embarrassment. / Oh, please hide and then come back out!
はい。ありがとうございます。楽しみにしてます。
Yes. / Thank you so much. I can't wait.
せっかくなんで、あの、来て、wacさん来ていただいたから、あの、なんかよかったら、あの、
Since we have this opportunity, with wac-san here, if you'd like...
直近に収録される楽曲を、あの、wacさんと一緒に、なんか、やりたいなと思うんですけど、歌います？
I was wondering if we could perform one of the songs that will be added soon, together with wac-san. Will you sing?
いいでしょう！せっかくなんでですね、あの、二人だけでやりましょう。
Sure thing! Since we're here, let's perform it with just the two of us.
あの、ピアノと歌だけで。
With just piano and vocals.
え！
What?!
エモくないですか？え、めちゃくちゃ嬉しい。緊張します。
Isn't that emotional? / Wow, I'm so incredibly happy. I'm getting nervous.
めちゃくちゃ緊張します、自分も。頑張ります。頑張ります！頑張ります！
I'm super nervous too. I'll do my best. / I'll do my best! I'll do my best!
頑張ります。実はね、練習してます、自分。このために。楽しみ！
I'll do my best. Actually, I've been practicing for this. / I can't wait!
はい、聴いていただきたい、ぜひ。はい。
Yes, I really hope you enjoy it. Yes.
では、えー、フレア、wacさんによる、聴いてください、
Well then, please listen to Flare and wac-san performing...
「僕の飛行機」
"Boku no Hikouki" (My Airplane).
どこまで飛べるかを
How far can we fly...
乗り込んだ汽車が
The train I boarded...
見上げた空へ 続くなら
...if it leads to the sky I looked up at.
夢をみてた遠い日に
On that distant day when I was dreaming,
取り残されてる記憶は
the memories left behind...
まだあの空を覚えているから
...still remember that sky.
絡み合って もつれ合って やがて一人
Intertwined, tangled up, eventually ending up alone...
さよならの歌 胸に約束を数えてるけど
...with a song of goodbye in my heart, counting my promises. But...
ここで見てた淡い夢も 翼にして
...turning even the faint dreams I saw here into wings,
きっとどこまでも追いつけると信じてる
I believe I can surely catch up no matter how far.
風に乗って 舞い上がって 蒼く溶けた
Riding the wind, soaring high, and dissolving into the blue,
あの紙飛行機は 誰の手に届いただろうか
in whose hands did that paper plane land?
夢が覚めて僕が空に還る時も
Even when the dream ends and I return to the sky,
ずっと変わらずに僕は君の中に生きている
I will always live on inside of you.
わあ！アレンジすごい！え、ありがとうございました！
Wow! That arrangement was amazing! Thank you so much!
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
メチャメチャ貴重な体験をさせていただきました。
I had such a wonderful and precious experience.
こちらこそ、ありがとうございました。
The pleasure is mine. Thank you very much.
はい、ありがとうございました！
Yes, thank you very much!
wacさんでした！
That was wac-san!
はい、作ってんのはこんなやつです。
Yes, I'm the guy who made it.
一言最後にあります？
Do you have a final word for us?
いや、もう本当にこの度は素晴らしい機会をいただきまして、こちらこそありがとうございました。
No, really, thank you so much for giving me this wonderful opportunity.
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
今後とも是非、pop'n music、BEMANIシリーズをよろしくお願いいたします。
Please continue to support pop'n music and the BEMANI series in the future.
よろしくお願いします！
Please do!
はぁー！いや、本当に嬉しいですね。大好きな「僕の飛行機」をwacさんと一緒にお届けしました！
Phew! I'm so happy. I performed my favorite song, "Boku no Hikouki", together with wac-san!
アレンジバージョンどうでしたか？めちゃ凄かったですよね！
How did you like the arranged version? It was absolutely amazing, wasn't it?
wacさんからご提案いただきまして、今回アレンジバージョンで歌わせていただきました。
Wac-san suggested it, so I got to sing the arranged version this time.
いくつもの夜を越えて
Crossing many nights,
紡いできた　自分らしさ
I have spun my own way.
選択したそのすべてが
All the choices I made
私をまた突き動かす
stir me into motion again.
強がってた訳じゃなくて
It wasn't that I was trying to be strong,
止まることが怖かったよ
I was just afraid to stop.
迷いながら選んだあの日もきっと
That day I was lost, surely,
今のチカラになってるよ
is becoming my strength now.
一人きりだと思っても
Even when I thought I was all alone,
気づけばそこにある笑顔が
if I realized it, the smile there
私といつも一緒に
was always...
歩いてくれてた
...walking by my side.
その意味　そのチカラ
That meaning, that strength,
絶対に離さない！
I will never let go!
加速していくこの想いは
This emotion that keeps accelerating
いま翼を纏い出す
is now starting to put on wings.
私が私でいれる
That I can be myself
それだけで十分だから
is enough, so...
逃げないって決めたのは
The reason I decided not to run away
強くなったからじゃない
is not because I became strong.
私を呼ぶその声と
With that voice calling me,
重ね合った
overlapping with mine,
信じる世界の明日を
I believe in the tomorrow of this world.
傷つくこと躊躇ってた（ためらってた）
I hesitated to get hurt,
立ち止まったこともあった
there were times I stood still.
そんな時にこの背中を
At such times, the gaze
押してくれたその眼差し
that pushed my back...
迷いながら選んだ道（みち）
The path I chose while wandering,
間違いさえ真実だと
even mistakes are the truth.
その焔は闇を照らして（てらして）
That flame lit up the darkness
私に正しさをくれた（くれた）
and gave me the path of right.
張り裂けそうに痛んでも
Even when it hurts so much it feels like tearing,
この胸に刻んだ勇気が
the courage carved in my heart...
私をいつも
was always...
支えてくれていたから
...supporting me, so...
今ここに感じ合う（かんじあう）
Now we feel each other here,
あなたと私の夢
your dream and mine.
燃え尽きることの無い夢は（ゆめは）
The dream that will never burn out,
この大空に羽ばたいて（はばたいて）
spreads its wings into this vast sky.
涙さえも輝かせ（かがやかせ）
Making even tears shine,
誰かの夜を照らしたい（てらしたい）
I want to light up someone's night.
逃げないって決めたのは（きめたのは）
The reason I decided not to run away
強くなったからじゃない（じゃない）
is not because I became strong.
静かな焔を抱いて（だいて）
Embracing a quiet flame,
何度だって（なんどだって）
again and again,
立ち上がること知ったから（しったから）
because I learned I can rise once more.
たとえ世界が色を失くし（うしない）
Even if the world loses its color
光が遠ざかっても（とおざかっても）
and the light fades away,
この名に刻む焔は（ほのおは）
the flame engraved in this name
あなたと私を繋いで（つないで）
will connect you and me.
いないよ！発表していくよ！
I'm not leaving! I'm going to announce them!
改めて、今回コラボするゲームは、pop'n music、DanceDanceRevolution、SOUND VOLTEXの3機種です！
To reiterate, the games we are collaborating with this time are Pop'n Music, DanceDanceRevolution, and Sound Voltex!
この3機種に、先ほど披露した「Silent Flame, Never Fade」が収録されます！
My original song 'Silent Flame, Never Fade,' which I performed earlier, will be included in these three games!
ご覧の日時からプレイすることができますので、お楽しみに！
You can play it starting from the dates shown on screen, so please look forward to it!
さらにさらに！不知火フレアが歌うBEMANIシリーズのカバー楽曲の収録も決定しました！
Furthermore! It has also been decided that my cover versions of BEMANI series songs will be included!
収録楽曲、収録機種、収録日時についてはご覧の通りです！
The songs, games, and release dates are as shown on the screen!
そして！まだまだ終わりません！
And! That's not all!
BEMANIアーティストとのコラボ新曲の制作が決定しました！
We've decided to produce a new collaboration song with a BEMANI artist!
続報はpop'n music公式Xで発信予定ですので、ぜひチェックしてみてください！
More information will be posted on the official Pop'n Music X account, so be sure to check it out!
さあ、ここからは各機種ごとのコラボ内容をまとめてご紹介していきます！
Now, let's look at the details of the collaboration for each game!
pop'n musicでは、なんと不知火フレアがポップンキャラとして登場しちゃいます！
In Pop'n Music, I, Shiranui Flare, will actually appear as a playable character!
さらに、ゲームをもっと楽しくプレイできる、コラボカスタマイズアイテムも登場します！
In addition, collaboration customization items that will make playing the game even more fun will be available!
詳細は追って公式Xにて発表予定なので、お見逃しなく！
Details will be announced later on the official X account, so don't miss it!
DanceDanceRevolutionでは、ゲーム画面の見た目を自分好みに変更できるプレミアムカスタマイザーとして、コラボアイテムが登場予定です！
In DanceDanceRevolution, collaboration items will be available as premium customizers that let you customize the game screen to your liking!
SOUND VOLTEXでは、これまでホロライブメンバーも登場してきたネメシスクルーに、不知火フレアも新規加入します！
In Sound Voltex, I will be joining the Nemesis Crew, where other Hololive members have also appeared!
さらに、カスタマイズアイテムとして登場予定です！
Furthermore, they will be available as customization items!
こちらも詳細は追って公式Xにて発表していくので、忘れずにチェックしてね！
Details for this will also be announced later on the official X account, so be sure to check!
ということで！今回はフレアがずっと愛してやまない、BEMANIシリーズのオリジナルソング縛りのライブがしたい！というね
So, this live concert was born from my dream of wanting to do a concert featuring only BEMANI series songs that I've always loved...
あの、完全にフレアのやりたい放題ライブの企画だったわけなんですが
It was a project where I basically got to do whatever I wanted...
そこからこんなにたくさんゲームに実装されてしまうなんて、いまだにちょっと現実味がありませんが
But to have so many of them actually implemented in the games, it still feels surreal.
長く愛しているBEMANIユーザー様も、末長く今後ともBEMANIシリーズのことをよろしくお願いします
To the longtime BEMANI fans, please continue to love and support the BEMANI series in the future.
あ、不知火フレアもよければよろしくお願いします！
And if you don't mind, please support me, Shiranui Flare, as well!
ということで、あの、音ゲーマー特有の、あれ、嬉しみですが…
So, it's that feeling of joy unique to rhythm gamers, but...
すでに遊んでいるエルフレはもちろん、まだ始めてないエルフレも、これを機に遊んでもらえたら嬉しいです！
Of course, to the Elfriends who already play, and to those who haven't started yet, I'd be happy if you'd take this opportunity to play!
そして新曲もね、この後MVが公開されるのと、0時にはリリースもされるので、たくさん聴いて、観てくれると嬉しいです！
Also, the MV for the new song will be released after this, and it'll be released digitally at midnight, so I hope you listen to it and watch it a lot!
あとグッズ！今回ですね、少し早めにお知らせさせていただいたので、さらっと振り返るね！
And the merch! Since we announced it a bit early today, let me briefly go over it again!
マフラータオル、タンブラー、ぬいぐるみ付きスマホショルダー、キャップ、シチュエーションボイス、フルセット！
Muffler towel, tumbler, plushie smartphone shoulder bag, cap, situation voice, and the full set!
どれも可愛くて使いやすいと思うので、ぜひお仕事だったりお出かけとか、スポーツとか、ゲームセンターとか行ったりとか、何でも使ってみてください！
I think they are all cute and useful, so please use them at work, on outings, doing sports, or when going to game centers!
グッズの販売はこの後21時半からなので、数量限定もたくさん用意しているので焦らずにね！
Merch sales will start from 21:30 right after this. We have plenty of limited quantity items prepared, so no need to rush!
裏話なんかは、また改めてお話しさせてください！
I'll share some behind-the-scenes stories on another occasion!
今回は思いもよらないことが本当にたくさん起きて、運営さんもKONAMIの皆さんも、エルフレのみんなも、感謝の気持ちでいっぱいです！
So many unexpected things happened this time. I'm filled with gratitude towards the staff, everyone at KONAMI, and all the Elfriends!
本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you so very much!
さあ、明日はゲームセンターに行っちゃう？行っちゃう？ね、一緒に行こう！あはは！
So, are you going to the game center tomorrow? Are you? Yes, let's go together! Ahaha!